Summary_

I'm a Master student at KAIST School of Computing, advised by Alice Oh. My current research focuses on the evaluation of LLMs, including but not limited to, (i) What to evaluate: Exploring the direction in which LLMs should progress and examining current LLM behavior from that perspective and (ii) How to evaluate: Developing evaluation frameworks that measure the true capabilities of LLMs.

Research Interests: Natural Language Processing, LLM, LLM evaluation

Education _____

Korea Advanced Institute of Science & Technology

Dajeon, Korea

M.S. Computer Science

Aug 2023-present

· Advisor : Alice Oh

Korea Advanced Institute of Science & Technology

Dajeon, Korea

B.S. Electronic and Electrical engineering

Feb 2019-Aug 2023

• GPA 4.02/4.3, Summa Cum Laude

• Major GPA 4.15/4.3

Publications _____

Uncovering Factor Level Preferences to Improve Human-Model Alignment

{Eunsu Kim, Juhyun Oh}*, Jiseon Kim, Wenda Xu, Inha Cha, William Yang Wang, Alice Oh Preprint Under Review, 2024

BLEnD: A Benchmark for LLMs on Everyday Knowledge in Diverse Cultures and Languages

Junho Myung*, Nayeon Lee*, Yi Zhou*, Jiho Jin, Rifki Afina Putri, Dimosthenis Antypas, Hsuvas Borkakoty, Eunsu Kim, Carla Perez Almendros, Abinew Ali Ayele, Víctor Gutiérrez-Basulto, Yazmín Ibáñez-García, Hwaran Lee, Sham-suddeen Hassan Muhammad, Kiwoong Park, Anar Sabuhi Rzayev, Nina White, Seid Muhie Yimam, Mohammad Taher Pilehvar, Nedjma Ousidhoum, Jose Camacho-Collados, Alice Oh

Neurips D&B 2024

CLIcK: A Benchmark Dataset of Cultural and Linguistic Intelligence in Korean

Eunsu Kim, Juyoung Suk, Philhoon Oh, Haneul Yoo, James Thorne, Alice Oh LREC-COLING, 2024

Multi-FAct: Assessing Factuality of Multilingual LLMs using FActScore

Sheikh Shafayat, **Eunsu Kim***, Juhyun Oh*, Alice Oh COLM 2024

The Generative AI Paradox on Evaluation: What It Can Solve, It May Not Evaluate

{Eunsu Kim, Juhyun Oh, Inha Cha}*, Alice Oh

EACL SRW 2024

Work In Progress _____

LLM-AS-AN-INTERVIEWER: Beyond Static Testing Through Dynamic LLM Evaluation

Eunsu Kim, Juyoung Suk, Seungone Kim, Niklas Muennighoff, Dongkwan Kim, Alice Oh Work in Progress

Domestic Publications

Korean Named Entity Recognition using D-Tag

Eunsu Kim, Sujong Do, Cheoneum Park

Proceedings of the 34th Annual Conference on Human and Cognitive Language Technology, 2022

Teaching Experience _____

December 3, 2024 1

^{*} denotes equal contributions

Teaching Assistant

AI Ethics Spring 2024

Counseling Assistant KAIST CS

Leader of Counseling Assistants in spring 2024 Fall 2023 - Spring 2024

Tutor KAIST

General Physics 1 Mar 2022 - Dec 2022

Tutor KAIST Center for Gifted Education

Math & Science Apr 2021 - Dec 2024

Tutor KAIST Center for Gifted Education

AI, Education Contents Production Sep 2023 - Dec 2023

Work Experience

Hyundai motors company, NLP team

Seoul, Korea

Mar, 2022 - Aug, 2022

KAIST

Internship · Joint model of Named Entity Recognition and Intent Classification using BERT via soft prompt tuning

• Automatically building dictionary of unlabeled NAMUWIKI data

Talks_____

Hanbat National University

Dajeon, Korea

Evaluating Large Language Models: A Perspective of Building Evaluation Benchmark Datasets

Jun 2024

Research Experience

KAIST NICA lab Dajeon, Korea

Individual Study Dec 2020 - Dec 2021

• Unmixing proteins in fluorescence cell images

• Advisor: Prof. Youngyu Yoon, KAIST electrical engineering

KAIST BISPL lab Dajeon, Korea

Individual Study Sep,2022 - Dec,2022

· Detecting disease of MRI lung images using Visual-language model via prompt-based method

Advisor : Prof. Jongchul Ye, KAIST Kim Jaechul Graduate School of AI

KAIST ALINIab Dajeon, Korea Jan, 2023 - Mar, 2023

Individual Study

• Solving Tabular data classification problems using Large Language Models

• Advisor : Prof. Jinwoo Shin, KAIST electrical engineering

KAIST NMSL lab Dajeon, Korea

• Developing Test-Time Adaptation method that works on Transformers

• Advisor : Prof. Sungju Lee, KAIST electrical engineering

The Many Voices of ChatGPT

Dajeon, Korea

Jan, 2023 - Mar, 2023

Mar,2023-Aug, 2023

• Exploring the Potential of ChatGPT for Korean: A Case Study of College Entrance and Proficiency Exams

· Advisor : Prof. Alice Oh and Prof. James Thorne,

Skills ___

Research Intern

Research Intern

Programming Python, PyTorch, Matlab, C

Scholarships & Awards _____

Next Generation Water Action 2022

1st prize of Ulsan challenge

Technical University of Denmark

2022

DECEMBER 3, 2024 2

KAIST Urban Grand Challenges 2022

KAIST Civil & Environmental Engineering

Excellence Prize 2022

National Science and Technology scholarship

Korea Student Aid Foundation 2020–2022

DECEMBER 3, 2024 3